Lizette Hurtado

UI Developer

Summary

Lizette Hurtado is a professional UI Developer with nine years of experience creating web applications. She has a keen eye for detail, superb aesthetic sense, and a deep passion for creating world class user experiences. She is hardworking, enthusiastic, and thrives in a collaborative environment.

Work experience

UI Developer 2015 - 2018

Apple, Inc.

User interface developer for global platform sales automation and demand generation internal web applications for Apple. Design manager for global platform web and iOS applications for Retail, Education and Enterprise teams worldwide.

- Developed Apple's internal marketing automation platform for targeting the correct audience as leads into the Customer Relationship Management system.
- Developed and managed design for Apple's internal web application for planning and executing events or a series of events.
- Developed and designed email and microsite landing pages for sales and marketing campaigns.
- Developed and designed DevOps web application platform.
- Helped lead design for internal iOS applications for Events and Apple's global CRM platform.

Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Backbone.js, jQuery, SASS, Grunt, Gulp, AJAX, JSP, XML, PHP, Sketch

UI Developer 2013 - 2015

Tata Consultancy Services

Part of the iLog team, responsible for the development and maintenance of iLogWebPay; a stateless, REST API-based, single page application, utilizing AngularJS as a JS MVC layer, and used HATEOAS for communicating application states between the front-end and back-end layers.

- Worked with UI/UX Designer to ensure iLogWebPay development pluged-in to IS&T technical design.
- Used AJAX to integrate REST API calls. Hooked-up all the web services from loading transaction summary details to loading list of cities for specified zip codes.
- Implemented localized static text, such as labels, messages and bundled into json files. These json files are packaged along with other static files (CSS, HTML, JS) and deployed to Apache/Akamai.
- Used regular expressions for validating billing information.
- Implemented omniture reporting for tracking web analytics.
- Used Modernizr for browser feature detection.
- Used Jenkins to build and deploy application to IT/UAT environments

Skills: JavaScript, AngularJS MVC, RequireJS, jQuery, Modernizr, Animate.css, HTML5, CSS, SASS, Grunt, Bower, AJAX, JSP

UI Engineer 2012 - 2013

PayPal, Inc.

Worked on the PayPal Here™ mobile web application —a PayPal mobile payment solution for smartphones.

Tablet Checkout module - mCommerce

- Helped build the iPad UI experience using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Worked closely with lead UI Engineer to allocate deliverables and bugs

PayPal Here™ Japan onboarding and receipts - Redesigned mobile application experience for android and iOS

- Architected, developed and implemented SMS receipt for UK and Japan, utilizing XML and working closely with back-end C++ lead
- Managed and maintained Android redesign of Softbank integration, responsible for implementing new requirements and communicating to QA all deployments and bug fixes

XO Optimization - Mobile and Web Applications

- Optimized and implemented A/B testing for UI button designs, utilizing LESS and HTML
- Supported iOS an Android development efforts including design, implementation and testing
- Debugged and optimized JavaScript for dynamic, interactive web platform

Skills: XML, HTML, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Dust, JavaScipt, jQuery, jqMobi

Web Developer 2011 - 2012

Trion Worlds, Inc.

Worked on all major marketing web applications for Trion Worlds, Inc., on team based development projects with an emphasis on HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

Defiance™ TV show and video game Web Application

- Created a new regionalized Defiance marketing website using JavaScript, jQuery and the latest technologies CSS3 and HTML5.
- Migrated code to WordPress
- Followed up with QA agencies and fixed bugs

End of Nations™ video game Web Application

- Redesigned End of Nations' marketing and community sites using HTML5
- Prototyped code to WordPress
- Followed up with QA team and fixed bugs

Trion Worlds, Inc. Corporate Web Application

- Maintained corporate website
- Re-wrote / polished CSS

Marketing and Account emails

- Revamped development for all marketing emails
- Produced hand-coded marketing and transactional cross-browser email templates across all major email clients

Skills: HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Javascipt, ¡Query, AJAX

Front-End Developer Intern

2009 - 2011

Hobson Manufacturing

Designed and developed multiple modules of the Hobson ERP application, such as Shipping, and Quotes, specializing in reusable user interface components.

Hobson Manufacturing ERP Application

- Created wireframes based on functional requirements provided by business users and project lead.
- Used HTML, CSS and JavaScript to implement user interface according to specifications.
- Implemented AJAX and JSON-driven UI components for managing critical business data.
- Used jQuery and dHtmlXgrid libraries to implement front end logic.
- Developed cross-browser compatible user interfaces, supporting Firefox, Chrome, and Safari web browsers.
- Maintained CSS stylesheets for modules.
- Worked in cooperation with back-end engineers and team lead to implement data management solution according to business requirements.

Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, dHtmlXgrid

One Team Technologies

Web User Interface developer on various web projects.

One Team Technologies Website

- Developed User Interface features using DHTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and AJAX according to screen flows, wireframes, and user interface specifications
- Integrated, formatted and maintained website content.
- Developed new pages and maintained internal navigation framework.
- Maintained and updated CSS stylesheets according to ongoing changes.
- Worked closely with senior lead to define styles and specifications for User Interface
- Prototyped styles and usability features using CSS, Javascript and HTML.

One Team Social Networking Site

- Developed front end components using DHTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query and AJAX.
- Created the main CSS stylesheet and unified style templates.
- Performed sanity testing on each new software build.
- Wrote test cases for the entire site based on written and verbal specifications.
- Designed graphics, and printable promotional materials using Adobe Creative Suite.

Skills: DHTML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX

Education

Web Developer Certification Program

2008 - 2009

Golden State Technology Institute

http://goldenstatetech.com | Graduate Program